LUSIO FILIBA, B.A. FOREIGN LANGUAGES, INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS & MARKETING

202. 549. 3431 | <u>LusioF@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>My Portfolio</u> | <u>International Patented Designs & Technologies</u>

1778 Willard Street, #1 | Washington, DC 20009

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Successfully generated revenue exceeding \$100mil while conducting business in 7 languages. Possessing 15-years of professional sales, consulting, technology sales and account management experience. Overseen growth of client services teams from 1 to a team of 15 and led growth to exceed \$100mil in less than a decade. Proven track record in security consulting, technology consulting, digital services, client partnerships, account and business management. Consistently exceeds quotas, budgets and increases profits. Lusio has Invented and Patented several, multi-million-dollar products that are internationally recognized and protected technologies. A skilled leader, manager and negotiator. Completed "first-of-kind" projects for the World Bank, The United States Senate in Washington D.C. (The Capitol), US Capitol Police, FIFA, BIG Data, US Nuclear and won master service level agreements for Technology Organizations, US Critical Infrastructure and Energy as well as, many Fortune 500 Companies. Lusio has created a legacy of winning groundbreaking projects and helping organizations strategize, build new business models and transition into the digital gig economy.

KEY CAREER ACHIEVEMENTS

 Led sales from \$0.00 in 2010 to \$60mil in 6 years 	Grew sales team from 1 to 15 in 6 years
 Developed, Invented & Patented New Technologies (click <u>here</u> to view) 	 Won "first-of-kind" Legacy Projects with Largest MSA Values in the Group's history
 Opened new market regions and created revenue in new industry verticals 	 Grew Revenues to Validate the purchase of a 120,000 sqft facility for the Group
 Successfully presented services and products to the United States Senate in Washington, D.C. 	Led & Won projects in more than 15 countries globally

KEY COMPETENCIES

KEY COMPETENCIES						
•	Technical/Engineering Sales Consulting, Technology Consulting	•	Marketing Strategy, Business Strategy, Business Plan			
	Services, Key Account Management, Business Management,	Development, White Papers, ASTM Standards & Specifications				
	Client Engagement, Presenting		(See my Portfolio <u>here</u>)			
•	Project Management	•	Product Development Partnerships			
•	Hiring & Training	•	Budgeting, Quotas, KPI's, Profit Generation			
•	Leadership, Client Relationship Management	•	Contract Negotiation, Project Financing			

CAREER HISTORY

COMPANY	TITLE ROLE	DATES
Bear Mountain Security LLC	Executive VP	11/22/2017 to Present
Cochrane USA Inc.	USA & Canada Territory Director	01/05/2010 to 11/09/2017
Cochrane Industries UK Ltd.	Business Development Executive	01/11/2009 to 01/04/2010

2017 To Present

Executive Vice President Bear Mountain Security: Consulting Risk Analysis Services, Professional Consulting Services Product Development, Client Engagement, Client Partnering. Professional Consulting Services in the Security and Technology Industry. Business Analysis, Digital Product Definition, Digital Product Strategy, Digital Product Validation, Digital Product Development & Engineering, Professional Consulting Services, Business and Use-case strategy.

- Professional risk analysis and product consulting services. Technical/Engineering sales consulting services, architectural design and engineering sales services.
- Business Management consulting developing new business plans for client partners.
- Consulting services to provide client latest risk mitigation strategies and best practices. Drives the client services mission, manages international and national partnerships, delivers presentations and closes business.
- Writes Proposals and negotiates contracts and project financing terms and conditions.
- Launch new products in the market and won "first-of-kind" contracts with the City of Los Angeles, CA, The City of Arlington, VA and The World Bank.
- Experienced in project life-cycle management.

2005 To 2017

USA & Canada Territory Director Cochrane USA Inc.: Trusted Client Advisor, Professional Consulting Services, Opened the Group's First Risk Mitigation Consulting Practice, Drive Business Change, Advises on Best Practices.

- Opened Cochrane USA's North American operation in 2010.
- Patented numerous market leading technologies to ensure the company's market share and differentiate its offerings.

LUSIO FILIBA, B.A. FOREIGN LANGUAGES, INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS & MARKETING



202. 549. 3431 | <u>LusioF@gmail.com</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>My Portfolio</u> | International Patented Designs & Technologies

1778 Willard Street, #1 | Washington, DC 20009

- Develop marketing and sales strategies for various market segments and recruit and train personnel for: DoD, Commercial, NGO's, Bio-tech, Tech, Energy and Top Fortune 500 Groups.
- Led sales from \$0.00 in 2010 to \$60mil at the close of 2017.
- Professional advisory and consulting services for the Group's key partners and clients.
- Write proposals, lead presentations, manage budgets, KPI's and set sales targets/quotas.
- Grow the Group's footprint to include offices in D.C., South Carolina, Texas, Los Angeles and Toronto, Canada.
- Direct contributor of revenue growth and market entry into new regions including: Canada, Afghanistan, Europe, and the Caribbean.
- Lead consultant at trade shows, conferences and leads business travel assignments.
- Ensuring business profitability and pipeline growth and conversion.

2009 To 2010

Business Development Executive Cochrane Industries UK Ltd.: Assigned to International Divisions in Europe to Provide New Business Models and Offerings, Provision of New Services and Engagements Models, Green fielding New Markets.

- Establish new business development units in the Group's European Head Quarters located in England reporting directly to the European President of the Group.
- The role's objectives included: new logo capture in the European based client services department, Account management and project-life-cycle management.
- Provision of new business models and technologies to clients.
- Net new logo capture resulting in net new revenue generation.
- Liaise with the Group's President and update sales forecasts, oversee marketing plan/collateral development and the Group's general growth within the region.
- Establish new services and products within the region and grow revenue.
- Identify trade conferences, magazines, online media and other marketing related forums to grow the Group's recognition and brand awareness.

LANGUAGES

English, Spanish, French, and Portuguese; proficient in Italian, Greek, German, and Dutch.

TECHNOLOGIES (Click here to see my Portfolio)

HTML	CSS	Bootstrap
JavaScript	Node.js	Handlebars
MongoDB	MySQL	jQuery
React.js	Data Structures	Heroku
Patented Products	Algorithms	Responsive Design

EDUCATION

- University of Johannesburg, Auckland Park, Republic of South Africa 2009, Bachelor's Degree in Languages and International Relations
- University of Maryland University College-Robert H Smith School of Business 2010 Bachelor's Equivalency Degree in Marketing
- NYACK-New York's Christian College-School of Business, Leadership and Business Administration 2016 Bachelor's Equivalency Degree in Marketing and Languages
- George Washington University College of Professional Studies
 2019 Certified Professional Studies Program in Computational Languages (Graduating April 2020)